{
  "heading": "Subject-Verb Agreement Part 1.",
  "topics": [
    {
      "heading": "Subject-Verb Agreement Part 1.",
      "questions": [
        {
            "questionNo": 1,
            "question": "On the second Sunday of every month, she goes out to buy biscuits, get her car washed, and meet Rose. Which is the finite verb in the sentence?",
            "options": [
                "Go",
                "To buy",
                "Get",
                "Meet"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 2,
            "question": "Honey tastes sweet.<br> Is the above sentence grammatically correct?",
            "options": [
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 3,
            "question": "The verb agrees with the preceding noun or sentence when using:",
            "options": [
                "Fractions",
                "Percentages",
                "Indefinite quantifiers",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 4,
            "question": "Seventy-two percent of these machines are outdated.<br> Is the above sentence grammatically correct?",
            "options": [
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 5,
            "question": "'Time' is frequently expressed by using a singular verb.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 6,
            "question": "Which sentence is grammatically correct?<br>I. Thirty percent of this mob is stupid <br>II. Thirty percent of this mob are stupid.",
            "options": [
                "None of them",
                "Both I and II",
                "Only I",
                "Only II"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 7,
            "question": "The verb agrees with the preceding noun or sentence when using indefinite quantifiers.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 8,
            "question": "Which is the finite verb in the sentence below:<br> 'They love eating continental cuisine.'",
            "options": [
                "Loved eating",
                "Love",
                "Eating",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 9,
            "question": "'Distance' is frequently expressed using a singular verb.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 10,
            "question": "In which case is the subject always placed after the verb?",
            "options": [
                "When there is a fraction",
                "When it starts with ‘here’ or ‘there’.",
                "When it starts without any subject",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 11,
            "question": "Which Subject-verb Agreement is expressed through the sentence below?<br> 'The majority has supported the ‘go green’ initiative.'",
            "options": [
                "When ‘majority’/’minority’ refer to an undetermined number greater or less than 50%, use a singular verb.",
                "When ‘majority’/’minority’ refers to a given percentage, you can use a singular or plural verb.",
                "When the ‘majority’ or ‘minority’ refers to a specific group of people, use a plural verb.",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 12,
            "question": "'Money' is frequently expressed using a singular verb.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 13,
            "question": "The verb agrees with the preceding noun or sentence when using fractions.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 14,
            "question": "…………………………….. prefixed by ‘the’ and used as plural nouns require a plural verb:",
            "options": [
                "Pronouns",
                "Nouns",
                "Adjectives",
                "Noun Equivalents"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 15,
            "question": "A number of monkeys were jumping on the terrace.<br> Is the above sentence grammatically correct?",
            "options": [
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 16,
            "question": "The number of doctors registered with this NGO is 37.<br> Is the above sentence grammatically correct?",
            "options": [
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 17,
            "question": "Which sentence is grammatically correct?<br>I. An 80% majority stand for the victim.<br> II. An 80% majority stands for the victim.",
            "options": [
                "Both I and II",
                "Only I",
                "Only II",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 18,
            "question": "Select the correct option with regard to the sentence below:<br> 'David seems to be sad.'",
            "options": [
                "Subject -Verb concord is missing.",
                "No correction needed.",
                "Both A and B",
                "Wrong verb-form is used."
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 19,
            "question": "The verb agrees with the preceding noun or sentence when using percentages.",
            "options": [
                "Correct",
                "Incorrect"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 20,
            "question": "A non-finite Verb does not agree with the subject.",
            "options": [
                "True",
                "False"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 21,
            "question": "Which sentence(s) is grammatically correct?<br>I. Half of the cake is gone.<br>II. Half of the cakes are gone.",
            "options": [
                "I only",
                "II Only",
                "Both I and II",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 22,
            "question": "Is the sentence below grammatically correct? <br>'One-fourth of the learners in Robert’s class have requested a short trip to the mountains.'",
            "options": [
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 23,
            "question": "Is the sentence below grammatically correct?<br> 'Sometimes two quarters of my office time is invested in site visits.'",
            "options": [
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 24,
            "question": "Choose the grammatically correct sentence.",
            "options": [
                "Horace misses his mother.",
                "I miss my mother.",
                "They miss their mother.",
                "She misses her mother.",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": 4
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 25,
            "question": "Is the sentence grammatically correct?<br>'Around 1% of the water on this planet is contained in snow and ice.'",
            "options": [
                "Yes",
                "No"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        }
    ]
    
    }
  ]
}
